# Faizan Raheem

Flat # 14, 4<sup>th</sup> Floor, Razzaq Square, Kharadar, Karachi.

Mobile: 0335-2154881| E-mail: <u>FaizanRaheem94@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/faizan-rahim-9b875499/</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Human Resource Personnel having 6 years of demonstrated history of working in the non-profit organization and manufacturing industry. Skilled in Microsoft Office, Communication, Management Information Systems (MIS), and Teamwork. Bachelor's degree holder with a focus in Business/Commerce. Can manage employee benefits to support the organization's strategic goals and competitive objectives. Able to formulate and ensure implementation of the policy framework related to compensation and staff benefits.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Assistant Manager HR – Compensation & Benefits

October 2017 – Present

**Crown Group of Companies** 

Looking after all four group companies comprises of 1000 (+) head count related but not limited to monthly payroll, time management cycle, bonus and incentive distribution, employee loan management, variable allowances, medical insurance facility management, performance appraisal cycle, and final settlements. Act as a consultant to Director HR in formulating policies and procedures, grading system/structures and total reward strategies planning, budgeting and execution.

Strong knowledge of principles and procedures for personnel compensation and benefits, labor relations and negotiation, and personnel information systems. Ability to understand business and management principles involved in strategic planning, resource allocation, human resources modeling, leadership technique, and coordination of people and resources.

Following is the overview of some of my key responsibilities;

- Assist in policy formulation, design and implement programs in the areas of Compensation and Benefits
- Assist in evaluating company programs and recommending best HR practices to the management that support attracting and retaining qualified employees.
- Initiating, processing and computing the annual salary review and the annual performance appraisals, including completion of necessary documentation.
- Coordinating for Appraisal & Salary Increment procedure of the employees.
- Overseeing day to day management of the compensation and benefit function.
- Catering to employee queries related to benefits and compensation, resolve problems related to access to or payment of benefits.
- Assist in ensuring strong checks and systems for compliance to company policies for leave and time schedule.
- Handling exit formalities of the employee including processing full and final settlements.
- Assist in completion of all processes, procedures and activities necessary for the administration of employee benefits such as medical, life insurance, other allowances including timely renewals of relevant policies.

### **HR Operations Coordinator**

Aug 2015- Oct 2017

### **Greenstar Social Marketing**

### **Key responsibilities**

- Leaves induction of all employees.
- Overtime induction of all employees.
- Filing all HR and Payroll **confidential** documents.
- Make Full and finals calculation of all Ex employee's
- Make every month third party salaries of employee's
- Maintain all Third party document regarding payments
- All departmental work on the add hock or regular basis.
- Maintain all permanent and contractual employs files.
- Facilitate All Employees regarding process of their OPD Medical Claims
- Make Budget Headcounts for all departments in annual budget activity
- Maintain All Addition & Deletion of Employees in Medical Health Insurance.
- Maintain monthly third party headcount and other related documents
- Hire Third party employee's on the request of respected departments
- Maintain Record of All Premium Payments of NJI Life & NJI Life (Health)
- Dispatching all the salary draft to the individual or their concern banks.
- Give Assistance to All Employees regarding their Medical Panel, Procedure & Polices.
- Arrange All Executive Medical Checkup with collaboration with NJI (New Jubilee Insurance)
- Entries of 600 employees time sheets in MIS system during the period of payroll processing.
- Assisted manager in the fields of finance, HR & Payroll and other related work.
- Assist Head HR in different activities i.e. Annual Headcount budget, annual Head count costing and other related work
- Assist Payroll manager and Assist Assistant Payroll manager in the field of bank i.e. Cheque depositing draft depositing cheque cancelation and other related work.

#### **Human Resource Officer**

**Greenstar Social Marketing** 

Aug 2014-July 2015

#### **Key responsibilities**

- Leaves induction of all employees.
- Overtime induction of all employees.
- Filing awl HR and Payroll **confidential** documents.
- Maintain all permanent and contractual employs files.
- Maintain Record of All Premium Payments of NJI & EFU
- All departmental work on the add hock or regular basis.
- Managing all personal records of employee's data bank.
- Facilitate All Employees regarding process of their Medical Claims
- Maintain All Addition & Deletion of Employees in Medical Insurance.
- Dispatching all the salary draft to the individual or their concern banks.
- Assisted manager in the fields of finance, HR & Payroll and other related work.
- Give Assistance to All Employees regarding their Medical Panel, Procedure & Polices.
- Arrange All Executive Medical Checkup with collaboration with NJI ( New Jubilee Insurance )
- Entries of 1400 employees time sheets in MIS system during the period of payroll processing.
- Assist Payroll manager and Assist Assistant Payroll manager in the field of bank i.e. Cheque depositing draft depositing cheque cancelation and other related work.

### **HR & Payroll Assistant**

Jan 2014- July 2014

**Greenstar Social Marketing** 

## **Key Responsibilities**

- Leaves induction of all employees.
- Filing awl HR and Payroll confidential documents.
- All departmental work on the add hock or regular basis.
- Maintain all permanent and contractual employs files.
- Managing all personal records of employee's data bank.
- Dispatching all the salary draft to the individual or their concern banks.
- Assisted manager in the fields of finance, HR & Payroll and other related work.
- Entries of 1400 employees time sheets in MIS system during the period of payroll processing.
- Assist Payroll manager and Assist Assistant Payroll manager in the field of bank i.e. Cheque depositing draft depositing cheque cancelation and other related work.

### RAF Project - Reasearch & Development

**Greenstar Social Marketing** 

Sep 2013-Dec 2013

### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Maintaining all files and Document of CMW's and Providers.
- Data entry of 300 CMW'S.
- Data entry of provider's from 14 districts of Sindh and Punjab.
- Assisted Project Manager in the fields of finance, HR and other related to the project.
- Any other work that is assigned to me by the supervisor i.e. (scanning, printing, photocopying etc).

Intern United Bank Limited

Taking care of customer service desk and responsible to coordinate all necessary functions which regards to Account Opening, Cheque Clearing, Remittances, Foreign Currency and Bank Financing.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### KASBIT

MBA – Human Resource Management

2017- On Going

#### REFERENCES

Will be furnished on request